[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
barbells are not optimal they're out
okay they limit your range of motion and
they fix your wrist in an unnatural
position which wreaks Havoc throughout
your whole body no dumbbells dumbbells
are too unstable they're not optimal
cables are also too unstable and they
only work one part of the strain curve
machines are body type dependent and no
matter how hard they try they don't
match the strength curve are you serious
body weight
too light that's never going to
stimulate growth you need to know
something about hypertrophy training
stability is the most important thing
right you cannot fire a cannon out of a
canoe if the muscles sense any
instability they won't fire optimally so
then machines are the most stable so
they'd be the best type of resistance
right but I thought you said machines
aren't always optimal you're actually
not allowed to question me until you
have these guns
now while we're on the topic of machines
whenever you do any upper body pressing
movement it needs to be converging they
need to be at an angle this way and
whenever you do a pulling exercise it
needs to be diverging that leads to
better hypertrophy outcomes that's
actually very interesting is there any
research on this or is that just Theory
yeah I'm actually glad you asked there
is definitely evidence exhibit a exhibit
B
all right another thing about
hypertrophy trading when you're doing
pressing movements you never want to
lock out you always keep the tension on
the intended Muzzle you don't want to
shift the tension away to the triceps so
just keep it right in here
never go too deep you never want to use
a completely full range of motion that's
recipe for disaster you know you go too
deep you're going to get hurt okay so
don't walk out don't go too deep so just
mid-range pulses then let's just move on
all right in the research stretched
position exercise are always superior
right you never have to do an exercise
that's hard in the contracted position
always just do exercise that are hard in
a stretch okay got it so that eliminates
lateral raises seated rows hip thrusts
and lying leg curls why are those
exercises popular then because people
are idiots they don't understand
biomechanics is like me okay now with
PEC training you always want to be like
an arrow not out like a t Okay this
fully stretches the pegs this does not
that's weird I feel more tension here
than here
what you feel is a lie now with lat
training you don't want to go overhead
like this that doesn't stretch your legs
you really want to go at an angle like
this okay this is what fully stretches
your legs that's weird I don't feel more
stretched this way than this way then
your body is stupid
rid of me this it's 20 22 and you're
still doing seven over rows all you're
doing is training your eructors and your
hamstrings your chest has to be
supported otherwise you're not working
your lats at all you're only training
Erectors and hammies oh stop right there
you never do narrow grip seated Rose all
right you need wide grip to maximize
retraction okay you can't maximize
scapular retraction here you got to be
here I mean I get your point but I feel
it more with a narrow grip I don't like
wide grip and also our theater Rose just
like bent over Rose like didn't you say
my chest has to be supported now don't
go getting cute with me little boy you
want to learn something or not
chin ups and pull Downs are out they
don't work your lats wait what riddle me
this the year is 2022 and this Joker
here is still doing military press all
right look military is out look there's
no moment on look when you do a front
raise look at that momentar when you do
military press there's no momentum
therefore it doesn't work the delts
follow the fibers they will never lead
you astray okay don't do front raises
right follow the fibers you need to go
cross body like this so like if I put my
hand right here
and I do
that motion
versus this Motion versus this motion I
feel this overhead press emotion a lot
more right here in the front delt so
you're saying it doesn't work at all I
mean I don't know how else to say this
follow the fibers when training
the rear delts you never want a straight
arm you always want to bend the arm and
do basically a rear delt rope this
increases range of motion
I don't feel more range of motion I mean
your body is idiotic that's already been
established are you serious it's 2022
and you're still doing front squats
front squats do not train your legs at
all they're only limited by your upper
body strength and core strength in fact
every type of squat why would you train
your legs by putting something here when
this is going to be the limiting factor
all right you want to train your legs
properly you want big quads your back
has to be supported so only leg presses
and hack squats when you train your
hamstrings with knee flexion exercises
you always want to be in post your
pelvic tilt if you into your pelvic tilt
that's an energy leak you're not doing
it right I thought you said length and
range of motion are important so
wouldn't anterior pelvic tilt length in
the hamstrings leading to a greater
effect you pompous little prick
deadlifts more like dead exercise all
right the others are the most overrated
movement sure they work a lot of muscle
but they don't maximally hit any muscle
you really want to work the hamstrings
get on the 45 degree hyper for more
stability and a greater stretch when
training glutes you never go full hip
thrust okay you just do pulses just the
top half okay so I think I understand so
range of motion and stretch are always
important except with the hip thrust
with every single other exercise you
want to go deep and get it full range
just not with the hip thrust Bingo now
you're getting it son
now for hypertrophy training second only
to stability is path of motion all right
where is the muscle shortest where is
the muscle longest connect those two
points and now we're talking so using
this concept this would be
one of the most lengthened positions for
the glutes and then this would be one of
the most shortened positions so then
using this path of motion concept
this would be the most optimal glute
exercise so I could just do this
and I don't have to do squats or hip
dust anymore also to maximize range of
motion then every bilateral
glute exercise we should knee valgus
because that increases the stretch and
every unilateral we should curtsy that's
correct
um
obviously yeah let's just move on okay
let's move on the biceps have the
greatest momentum the greatest leverage
at 90 degrees when you go too low or too
high the moment arm drastically reduces
so just don't even go there just stay
right in here
so you're saying if a muscle has a poor
moment arm and a stretch then we
shouldn't go deep into the stretch but
doesn't that contradict everything
you've been saying I said momentar I
don't know the time or the energy
explain it to you Google it moment r
ow don't get me wrong bro I've
appreciated this experience because I
value people's opinions right I like
hearing different perspectives on things
but uh to be honest you don't know what
the hell you're talking about you need
to learn the difference between opinion
and fact all right
perfectly fine stating your opinion just
don't be a dick and quit posing things
as factual when you don't have evidence
for it
who it's true I'm a tick tock optimal
biomechanics bro please don't tell
anyone you'll ruin me please please keep
it secret and another thing do different
types of rows do different types of
presses do different types of squats
variety is the spice of life